Emma:	“Welcome to Denver Airport. How can I help you today?”
I handed my passport and flight confirmation to the woman at the United Airlines check-in.
I was on my way to Costa Rica at the beginning of the trip of a lifetime,
traveling around Central America.
The woman checked in my backpack and handed me my boarding pass.
“Lucky you, going to California,” she smiled. “Your gate is 37C.”
“No. I booked a ticket to San José.”
“Yes, Ms. Benns. Your ticket is for San José, in California.”
I was horrified! “I’m so sorry, but I need your help. My ticket is for the wrong San José.”
This time she didn’t smile.
She pointed to the help desk for United Airlines.
The next few hours were terrible.
The help desk assistant wasn’t helpful.
“I’m sorry. We can’t change your ticket.”
I tried to call my travel agent, hoping they could solve the problem.
No luck.
A message arrived on my phone from my dad.
It was a link to the Dionne Warwick song "Do you know the way to San Jose?"
Not funny, Dad.
Then a new attendant arrived. "What’s the problem?" she asked.
I explained the situation.
“Of course we can book a new flight for you, Ms. Benns.” I hugged her.
She immediately booked me onto a cheap flight to San José, Costa Rica.
Suddenly, I remembered my backpack.
But it was too late.
“Did you check in my luggage?” I asked.
“No. Unfortunately, it’s on the way to California.”
So, after 72 hours, four flights, and three days without luggage,
I can say that I know the long way to San José.
And I have one important lesson for you:
always take spare underwear in your carry-on luggage.
And if you can fit extra jeans, a T-shirt, and a sweater in there, too, DO THAT!